<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="dde_seat">
  <copyright><![CDATA[
        Copyright © 2020  wugang <wugang@uniontech.com>

        Permission to use, copy, modify, distribute, and sell this
        software and its documentation for any purpose is hereby granted
        without fee, provided that the above copyright notice appear in
        all copies and that both that copyright notice and this permission
        notice appear in supporting documentation, and that the name of
        the copyright holders not be used in advertising or publicity
        pertaining to distribution of the software without specific,
        written prior permission.  The copyright holders make no
        representations about the suitability of this software for any
        purpose.  It is provided "as is" without express or implied
        warranty.

        THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES WITH REGARD TO THIS
        SOFTWARE, INCLUDING ALL IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND
        FITNESS, IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY
        SPECIAL, INDIRECT OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR ANY DAMAGES
        WHATSOEVER RESULTING FROM LOSS OF USE, DATA OR PROFITS, WHETHER IN
        AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS ACTION,
        ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE USE OR PERFORMANCE OF
        THIS SOFTWARE.
        ]]></copyright>

  <description summary="protocol to get global input events">
  </description>

  <interface name="dde_seat" version="1">
    <description summary="get pointer objects">
      A global interface used for getting the global seat object for a
      given input device.
    </description>

    <request name="get_dde_pointer">
      <description summary="get a pointer object">
      get a pointer through a global seat object
      </description>
      <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="dde_pointer"/>
    </request>
  </interface>

  <interface name="dde_pointer" version="1">
    <description summary="relative pointer object">
      A dde_pointer object is an extension to the wl_pointer interface
      used for emitting global pointer events.
    </description>

    <request name="get_motion">
      <description summary="get a global cursor position">
      </description>
      client request server to send a global cursor position
    </request>

    <event name="motion">
      <description summary="pointer motion event">
      server send a global cursor position to client
      </description>
      <arg name="x" type="fixed" summary="global x coordinate"/>
      <arg name="y" type="fixed" summary="global y coordinate"/>
    </event>

    <enum name="button_state">
      <description summary="physical button state">
      Describes the physical state of a button that produced the button
      event.
      </description>
      <entry name="released" value="0" summary="the button is not pressed"/>
      <entry name="pressed" value="1" summary="the button is pressed"/>
    </enum>

    <event name="button">
      <description summary="pointer button event">
      Mouse button click and release notifications.

      The button is a button code as defined in the Linux kernel's
      linux/input-event-codes.h header file, e.g. BTN_LEFT.

      Any 16-bit button code value is reserved for future additions to the
      kernel's event code list. All other button codes above 0xFFFF are
      currently undefined but may be used in future versions of this
      protocol.
      </description>
      <arg name="x" type="fixed" summary="global x coordinate"/>
      <arg name="y" type="fixed" summary="global y coordinate"/>
      <arg name="button" type="uint" summary="button that produced the event"/>
      <arg name="state" type="uint" enum="button_state" summary="physical state of the button"/>
    </event>

  </interface>

</protocol>
